# **CHRIS VALMONTE**

### **Design Technologist**

chrisvalmonte.com

in linkedin.com/in/chrisvalmonte

I create web products that are usable, responsive, and delightful. With my background in computer science and interest in UI/UX design, I am passionate about making technology easier for experts and non-experts to use. My work isn't work because I love doing it. In my spare time, I enjoy playing video games, watching Disney movies, and sprinkling my design/development dust across the web.

## **SKILLS**

### Coding

HTML5

CSS3 & SCSS

JavaScript & JQuery

**NodeJS** 

Bootstrap

C#

C++

Python

Ruby on Rails

### Design

Responsive Web Design
Mockups/Wireframes/Prototypes
A11y & Usability

#### **Toolkit**

Atom

Adobe Creative Cloud Browser Developer Tools GitHub & Git CLI

Trello/Asana

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Code Publishing Co. **Front-End Developer**

11/2016 - 02/2018 Seattle, WA

- Based off of provided user research, applied common user interface patterns to design alternatives.
- Utilized Adobe Creative Cloud, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build innovative and responsive UI solutions for clientele.
- Developed an SCSS variable system for the customization of web interfaces, which cut development time by 33%.
- Conducted research on competitor web offerings and empathetically designed new features based on my findings.

## Expedia Group Capstone Project - Team Member

09/2015 - 06/2016 Seattle, WA

- Oversaw development using Agile and Scrum, gathered complex requirements, and implemented a successful MVP.
- Created wireframes and user interface flow diagrams.
- Developed 80% of the front-end for demos with stakeholders, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

## **EDUCATION**

Seattle University **BS, Computer Science** 

09/2012 - 06/2016 Seattle, WA

## **SELECTED PROJECTS**

#### **Hotels Now (Capstone)**

- Documented and developed a fully automated web app.
- Set up schedules, delegated sprint tasks, and cleared roadblocks impeding my team.

### **Government Web Interfaces**

Customized pixel-perfect interfaces using SCSS, including:

- bellevue.municipal.codes
- jasper.county.codes
- wiyot.tribal.codes

### nwfasaisangbagsak2017.com

- Implemented a website for the NWFASA's 22nd conference.
- Saved the committee hundreds of dollars as they did not need to print programs for the event.